A Guide to the Leesburg Garden Club Collection, 1920-
Thomas Balch Library
- (Box 8)
  - Garden Week, Little Oatlands-photograph, 1981
  - Garden Week, hostess list, 1981
- (Box 9)
  - Garden Week, Brochures (Fauquier-Loudoun area), 1982
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," booklet, brochures (4 copies), 1983
  - Garden Week, Information for chairman, 1983
  - Garden Week, Information about houses (Old Stone Meeting House, Goose Creek Friends Meeting House, Somerset, Lark Rise, Oakland Green, Wenona, Stonecrest), 1983
  - Garden Week, publicity, 1983
  - Garden Week, chronology, 1983
  - Garden Week, correspondence re: invitations and thank-you notes, 1983
  - Garden Week, Lincoln area: brochures (4 copies), badge, 1985
  - Garden Week, publicity and photographs, 1985
  - Garden Week, history of Lincoln area and description of tour, 1985
  - Garden Week, correspondence (general), 1985
  - Garden Week, correspondence with GCV, 1985
  - Garden Week, advertising, 1985
  - Garden Week, addresses, 1985
  - Garden Week, letters regarding complimentary tickets, 1985
  - Garden Week, letter to homeowners, 1985
  - Garden Week, signs (VDOT), bus tours, box lunches, 1985
  - Garden Week, expenses, receipts, 1985
  - Garden Week, "things to remember", 1985
  - Garden Week, Annual Report, 1985
- (Box 10)
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun area, ticket, 1986
  - Garden Week, "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," book, 1987
  - Garden Week, chairman's report, 1987
  - Garden Week, brochure and ticket (Oak Hill, Little Oatlands, Oatlands Hamlet, Cox House (10 Cornwall St. N.E.), Rock Spring Farm, McElhinney House (Ayr St. S.W.), Norris House (Loudoun St. S.W.), Westmoreland Davis Equestrian Institute), 1987
  - Garden Week, advertising and business, 1987
  - Garden Week, buses and parking, 1987
  - Garden Week, committees, 1987
  - Garden Week, houses, staffing, and instructions, 1987
  - Garden Week, letters about complimentary tickets, 1987
  - Garden Week, publicity (1 of 2), 1987
  - Garden Week, publicity (2 of 2), 1987
  - Garden Week, brochures (4 copies) and advertising, 1989
  - Garden Week, chairman & committees, 1989
  - Garden Week, publicity, 1989
  - Garden Week, houses, Leesburg area, photographs, 1989
  - Garden Week, complimentary tickets, 1989
  - Garden Week, correspondence, 1989
  - Garden Week, financial, 1989
  - Garden Week, houses, hostesses, 1989
  - Garden Week, brochure (3 copies) northwest Leesburg, 1991
  - Garden Week, chairman's report, 1991
  - Garden Week, complimentary tickets, 1991
  - Garden Week, committees, 1991
  - Garden Week, financial, advertising, 1991
  - Garden Week, hostesses, 1991
  - Garden Week, instructions to chairman & committees from GCV, 1991
  - Garden Week, publicity, 1991
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, brochure, 1992
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, statewide guidebook, 1992
- (Box 11)
  - Garden Week, brochures, 1993
  - Garden Week, instructions from the GCV, 1993
  - Garden Week, chairman and committees, 1993
  - Garden Week, publicity, 1993
  - Garden Week, complimentary tickets, 1993
  - Garden Week, correspondence, 1993
  - Garden Week, Dodona Manor, 1993
  - Garden Week, financial, 1993
  - Garden Week, houses and hostesses, 1993
  - Garden Week, parking and transportation, directional signs by Virginia Department of Transportation (VDOT), 1993
  - Garden Week, signs, 1993
  - Garden Week, miscellaneous notes, 1993
  - Garden Week, future, 1993
  - Garden Week, GCV information, 1995
  - Garden Week, brochures, ticket, 1995
  - Garden Week, advertising, 1995
  - Garden Week, bus tours, 1995
  - Garden Week, correspondence, 1995
  - Garden Week, publicity, 1995
  - Garden Week, financial, insurance, 1995
  - Garden Week, houses and hostesses (Lincoln area), 1995
  - Garden Week, schedule and committees, 1995
  - Garden Week, VDOT signs, parking, 1995
  - Garden Week, suggestions for future, 1995
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, 1996
  - Garden Week, GCV information, 1997
  - Garden Week, brochure, Town of Leesburg, 1997
  - Garden Week, chronology, 1997
  - Garden Week, publicity (1 of 2), 1997
  - Garden Week, publicity (2 of 2), 1997
  - Garden Week, houses and hostesses, 1997
  - Garden Week, Ashbaugh house (420 W. Market St.), 1997
  - Garden Week, Blum house (211 Cornwall St. N.W.), 1997
  - Garden Week, Cook house (Rock Spring Farm), 1997
  - Garden Week, Cox house (10 Cornwall St. N.E.), 1997
  - Garden Week, Devine house (215 Cornwall St. N.W.), 1997
  - Garden Week, Norris House (Loudoun St. S.W.), 1997
  - Garden Week, buses, transportation, VDOT, 1997
  - Garden Week, financial, 1997
  - Garden Week, ticket, attendance, 1997
  - Garden Week, chairman's notes and suggestions, 1997
- (Box 12)
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, "Garden Week in Virginia" GCV book, 1998
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, brochures, 1998
  - "Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, 1999
  - Garden Week, GCV information, 1999
  - Garden Week, brochures (4 copies), tickets, 1999
  - Garden Week, chronology, 1999
  - Garden Week, committees, 1999
  - Garden Week, correspondence, 1999
  - Garden Week, hostesses, flowers, insurance, 1999
  - Garden Week, houses, 1999
  - Garden Week, publicity (1 of 2) (Route 15 north area), 1999
  - Garden Week, publicity (2 of 2), 1999
  - Garden Week, signs (VDOT), 1999
  - Garden Week, financial, 1999
  - Garden Week, general suggestions, 1999
  - "Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, 2000
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, brochure, 2000
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, publicity, 2000
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, 2001
  - Garden Week, brochures (5 copies), tickets, 2001
  - Garden Week, committees, 2001
  - Garden Week, publicity (Waterford area), 2001
  - Garden Week, houses, 2001
  - Garden Week, hostesses, flowers, 2001
  - Garden Week, correspondence, 2001
  - Garden Week, VDOT signs, 2001
  - Garden Week, financial, 2001
- (Box 13)
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Middleburg area, 2002
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, 2003
  - Garden Week Along the Carolina Road brochures, tickets, 2003
  - Garden Week, publicity, 2003
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Rectortown area, 2004
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Rectortown area, 2004
  - "Historic Garden Week in Virginia," GCV book, 2005
  - Garden Week, Northwest Cornwall St., Leesburg, brochures, 2005
  - Garden Week, chairman and committees, 2005
  - Garden Week, N.W. Cornwall St., Leesburg, owners, 2005
  - Garden Week, Northwest Cornwall St., hostess information, 2005
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, Upperville area, 2006
  - Garden Week, general information, 2007
  - Garden Week, brochure and ticket, Lincoln area, 2007
  - Garden Week, chairman and committees, 2007
  - Garden Week, publicity, 2007
  - Garden Week, photographs of houses, 2007
  - Garden Week, owners, 2007
  - Garden Week, hostesses, 2007
  - Garden Week, signs inside houses, 2007
  - Garden Week, tour groups, 2007
  - Garden Week, insurance, 2007
  - Garden Week, financial, 2007
- (Box 14)
  - Garden Week, Fauquier-Loudoun Garden Club, brochures, Middleburg area, 2008
  - Garden Week, brochures, along the Potomac River, 2009
  - Garden Week, letter re: elimination of Sunday tour, 2010
  - Garden Week, brochure, Mount Gilead area, 2011
- (Box 15)
  - Leesburg Garden Club program, 1920
  - Leesburg Garden Club programs, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936
  - Leesburg Garden Club programs, 1937, 1939, 1940, 1941
  - Leesburg Garden Club program, 1941
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1946, 1947, 1948, 1949
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1950, 1951
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1955
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1956, 1957, 1958, 1959, 1960
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1961, 1962, 1963, 1964
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1965, 1966, 1968, 1969
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1970, 1982, 1986, 1987, 1988, 1989
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1990, 1991, 1992, 1993
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 1998, 1999, 2000, 2002
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 2003, 2004, 2006
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 2007, 2008
  - Leesburg Garden Club yearbooks, 2009, 2010
- (Box 16)
  - GCV Register, 1956-57
  - GCV Register, 1969-70
  - GCV Register Supplement, 1987-88
  - GCV Register, 1992-93
  - GCV Register Supplement, 1997-98
  - GCV Register, 2000, 2001
  - GCV, 2002-2003
  - GCV, 2004-2005
  - GCV, 2006-2007
  - GCV, 2008-09, 2010
  - GCV Members Handbook, 1983
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 1995
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 1996
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 2000
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 2001
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 2004
  - GCV Annual Meeting, 2006
  - GCV Board of Governors' Meeting, 1994
  - GCV Board of Governors' Meeting, 1999
  - Leesburg Garden Club flower show teams, 2005-2006
  - GCV Lily Show schedule, GCV Lily Show schedule
- (Box 17)
  - GCV presidents of member clubs, 1996-1997
  - GCV Year in Review, 2008-2009
  - GCV Year in Review, 1 July 2009-30 September 2010
  - Styles of Flower Arranging: A Primer 1996, 2006
- (Box 18)
  - Iris: Leesburg Garden Club flower
  - Gift of records to Thomas Balch Library, 2006
  - Historian: duties, 1999
  - GCV, Guidelines for Historians, 2006
  - GCV history
  - "Follow the Green Arrow" excerpts re: Leesburg Garden Club, 1920-1930, 1970-1995
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1964-March 1965
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1965, March 1969
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1970-1976
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1970-1994
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1982-1984, 1984-1986
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1990, 1991
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 1994-2000
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 2004, 2005, 2006
  - Leesburg Garden Club history, 2007, 2008
  - Historian's annual reports
  - Schools Beautification, 1938-1960s
  - Coalition for Loudoun, late 1980s
  - Awards
  - Massie Medal winners, 1929-2001
  - Common Wealth Award, 1982
  - Flower shows: general information
  - GCV Flower Show Handbook, 1974
  - GCV Daffodil Show, Roanoke: photographs, 1977
  - GCV Lily Show, photographs, 1980
  - GCV Daffodil Show, Danville: schedule, 1996
  - GCV Daffodil Show, Leesburg (see also scrapbook 1991-2007), 2002, 2003
  - Rose Test Chairman's Duties, 1994
  - "Historic Preservation" with article on Oatlands featuring Joan Stafford-Allen Williams
  - "Policies, Precedents and General Information"
- (Box 19)
  - By-laws as amended, 11 November 1997
  - Tree Ordinance committee, report and recommendations to town of Leesburg, 1994
  - Incorporation and 501c3 tax status, 1999
  - Policy Review Committee, 1997
  - Rust Sanctuary Gardens, 2001
  - Rust Sanctuary Gardens, photographs, 2001
  - Proposed Rain Garden at White's Ferry on Rockland property, 2004
  - Proposal for garden library at Oatlands, 1995
  - Speakers list, 1994
  - A member's Horticultural Experiences, 1993
  - Silent auction
  - Nature Camp
  - Notecard sample
  - "Gardening Without Poisons," 1963
  - Christmas raffle, 1994
  - Dirt Roads Tour: Lincoln Community League, 1974
  - Plant sale, 1975
  - Information about Agnes Harrison
  - "A Floral Menu," 1996
  - Honorary membership
  - Correspondence
  - Oak Hill - photographs
  - Loudoun County Day at Oatlands, 1981
  - Publications Committee, 1987-1992
  - Correspondence (donations)
  - Letter to New Members, 1966
  - Letter to New Members, 1990s
  - Sample letters, 1990s
  - Billboards-History of Zoning Ordinance
  - Zoning Ordinance-initial adoption
  - Sign Ordinance and zoning history: Washington Post, 16 April 2000
  - Signs and zoning: Vinton Pickens' talks, 1966 or 1967
  - State sign ordinance re: billboards on highways, 1970s-1990s
  - Sign Ordinance: signs in VDOT right-of-way, 1995
  - Sign Ordinance: influence of special interest groups
  - Sign Ordinance: violations, 1987, 1994, 1995
  - Sign Ordinance: violations, 1994
  - Sign Ordinance: violations, 1994
  - Sign Ordinance: violations, 1994
  - Sign Ordinance: violations, 1996
  - Sign Ordinance-illegal signs, 2009
  - Sign Ordinance: report of sign committee, 1994
  - Proposed Sign Ordinance revisions re: wayside stands, 1996
  - Loudoun County Sign Ordinance (revised), 1998
  - Sign Ordinance: including collection of illegal signs, 2008-2011
  - Sign Ordinance: County and volunteer collection of illegal signs
  - Sign Ordinance, revised 2011: Loudoun Times Mirror, 6 February 2011
- (Box 20)
  - Annual Reports, 1963-1964
  - Annual Reports, 1964-1965
  - Annual Reports, 1965-1966
  - Annual Reports, 1966-1967
  - Annual Reports, 1967-1968
  - Annual Reports, 1969-1970
  - Annual Reports, 1970-1971
  - Annual Reports, 1971-1972
  - Annual Reports, 1972-1973
  - Annual Reports, 1973-1974
  - Annual Reports, 1974-1975
  - Annual Reports, 1975-1976
  - Annual Reports, 1977
  - Annual Reports, March 1978
  - Photographs, meeting in spring, 1994
  - Annual Reports, 1996, 1997, 1998
  - Annual Reports, 1999-2000
  - Annual Reports, 2000-2001
  - Annual Reports, 2001-2002
  - Annual Reports, 2003-2004
  - Annual Reports, 2003-2004
  - Annual Reports, 2004-2005
  - Annual Reports, 2005-2006
  - Annual Reports, 2006-2007
  - Annual Reports, 2007-2008
  - Annual Reports, 2008-2009
  - Annual Reports, 2009-2010
- (Box 21)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Journal, Instructions for submissions
  - GCV Journals, September 1967, November, December 1978, 1985
  - GCV Journals, October 1986; March, April 1987; March 1994
  - GCV Journals, March 1998, September 1998, September 2002, June 2003, September 2003
  - GCV Journals, June 2006, December 2005
  - GCV Journals, June, September, December 2007
  - GCV Journals, June 2008
  - GCV Journals, March, June, December 2009
  - GCV Journal, March 2010
  - GCV Journal, March 2011
  - Follow the Green Arrow Vol. II, The History of the Garden Club of Virginia, 1997
- (Box 22)
  - Exhibits Committee: duties and information, 2002 with 2008 addenda
  - Exhibit and hostess records, May 1938-April 1947
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1947, 1948, 1949
  - Exhibit ribbons, 1950
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1950, 1951
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1952, 1953
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1954-1955
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1956, 1957
  - Exhibits and hostess records, March 1958
  - Exhibits and hostess records, March 1959-July 1960
  - Leesburg Garden Club Daffodil Show, 11 April 1961
  - Exhibits and hostess records, August 1961-November 1963
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1964
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1965
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1966, 1967
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1968
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1969
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1970
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1971
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1972
  - Exhibits and hostess records, January-October 1973
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1975
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1976
  - Exhibits and hostess records, 1977 and January, February 1978
  - Exhibits chairman's annual reports, 1991, 1996, 1998, 1999
  - Exhibits chairman's annual reports, 2000-2008
- (Box 23)
  - negatives, 1997
  - negatives, 1999
  - 1999
  - Temple Hall, 22 slides
  - Sunnyside, 7 slides
  - Montresor, 13 slides
  - Christ Church, Lucketts, 17 slides; 1 slide of the old Lucketts school
  - Rockland (1 of 2), 15 slides
  - Rockland (2 of 2), 14 slides
  - Daydream, 9 slides
  - Noland's Ferry, 21 slides
  - Flower arrangements, 11 slides
  - Unidentified, interiors and gardens, 20 slides
- (Box 24)
  - President's report/calendar, 2008
  - President's information, 2008 - 2010
  - Treasurer's report, 2004 mid-year
  - Budgets, 2005-06, 2006-2007
  - Budget, 2008
  - Budget, 2009-2010
  - Budget, 2010-2011
  - Budget, 2011-2012
- (Box 011)
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1955
  - Garden Week Scrapbooks, 1954-1959
  - Scrapbooks, 1975-1983, 1983-1987, 1988-2001
  - Scrapbook, 1991-2007